Priyesh Vishwakarma

DevOps/Cloud Engineer

priyeshvkarma@outlook.com https://linkedin.com/in/vkpriyesh

OBJECTIVE

More than 3 years of technical expertise in implementing DevOps practices using Azure DevOps along with migration activities in different DevOps scenario. Created, deployed and managed applications on Azure and AWS stack with CI/CD implementation in agile methodology under Finance and Education domain.

EXPERIENCE

Bangalore, India TechStar India January 2020 – Present

• Client - Mindtree - Azure Infra Automation

- Role: DevOps Engineer
 - Extensive usage and implementation of RBAC, AD and subscription for different team subsets
 - Implementing Azure pipelines to support automated deployment with ARM templates of Azure Storage, SQL,
 VNETs and VMs
 - Implemented Sonar Cloud integrated with Azure DevOps to provide code coverage and code analysis results
 - Created build pipelines for .NET and .NET Core based application
 - Created release pipeline for multi-staging environment deployment
 - Monitoring alerts/issues using Application insights, Azure Monitor

Indore, India InfoBeans August 2019 – December 2019

Book Publishing Web App

- Role: DevOps Engineer
 - Implemented Azure storage integration with legacy web application to remove dependency of on premise file servers
 - Created function app to support frequent workloads that increased efficiency of application in terms of cost, loadtime consumption
 - Removed manual deployment dependency by implementing Azure DevOps pipelines
 - Created powershell scripts and YAML for custom task handling
 - Implemented branching strategy and strict branch policies to handle git workflow through Azure DevOps
 - Created PoC on Terraform deployment for Azure resource group, function & storage deployment

Pune/Indore, India

Tata Consultancy Services

November 2016 – August 2019

- Client McGraw Hill Education (Learning Management System Integration)
 - Role: DevOps Engineer
 - On premises application and DB migration to Azure VMs and Azure SQL
 - Managed re-architecture of legacy MVC web application to Azure services
 - Developed features in function app with C# .net core to support workflow automation
 - Developed code-base with C# on Azure services: Event Bus, Queues, Storage, Blob for persistent data access and communication across functions
 - Defined workflows in logic apps to manage frequent activities in application
 - Created CI/CD pipeline for on-prem build and deployment as well as for Azure services using ARM templates and YAML under Azure DevOps
 - Facilitating migration of tasks to Jira so as to implement robust Agile culture
 - Migrated TFS code base to Azure DevOps git Repos
 - Setup organisation, branching, build and release policies and triggers under Azure DevOps
 - Created build pipeline under Azure DevOps pipelines using YAML for .NET MVC application and function apps
 - Configured release pipeline using Azure DevOps pipelines and ARM templates to deploy, and configure resources on Azure
 - Developed powershell scripts to automate service executions and job scheduling
 - Analysed issues along with the root cause and provided solutions by utilising Application insights, Sumo Logic and New Relic within given SLA with RCA document creation on Confluence
 - Presented major changes in CAB meetings with handling pager duty
 - Worked on Enterprise Github through git CLI and Github desktop for source control management
 - Facilitated scrum in Agile Methodology Jira as a Task Management tool

- Client Microsoft Corp. (Finance Web Application)
 - o Role: .NET Developer /DevOps Engineering
 - Developed functionality in C# .NET 4.5 for an MVC based web application
 - Created TFS policies for better utilisation of check-in/check-out/shelveset functionalities
 - Managed on-prem TFS server for multi-stack application
 - Created scheduling scripts for batch jobs
 - Migrated TFS code base to Azure DevOps
 - Migrated code base from TFS to Azure DevOps and supported in building CI/CD pipeline for .NET applications
 - Automated deployment of web applications on Azure VMs using ARM templates
 - Used VSTS and Git for workflow and SCM

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Primary SkillSet: PowerShell, ARM Templates, Azure DevOps Build/Release, YAML, Azure Storage, Functions, Logic Apps, Runbooks, Dev Test Lab, VM, VNET
- Secondary SkillSet: SumoLogic, Terraform, .NET-C#
- Azure, Azure DevOps, Git, GitHub, Jira, Confluence, Windows, Linux Distros

EDUCATION

Degree Name	Institution Name	Grades/Percentage	Year
Bachelors of Engineering in	Medicaps Institute of	6.49/10.0	2016
Computer Science and Engineering	Technology and Management, Indore (India)		
Secondary School	Advanced Academy, Indore (India)	86.8%	2012
High School	Advanced Academy, Indore (India)	9.4/10	2010

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACTIVITIES

TCS Cloud Hackathon runner-up
Diploma in Experiential Education and Practices
Telegram Support Initiative Volunteer
Microsoft Student Partner

November 2018 March 2018 April 2016 – July 2016 November 2015 – August 2016

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : 21st July 1995

Nationality : Indian

Interests : Photography, Volunteering, Blogging